Smit Nirmal

🗣 M1V3C5, Canada 🔀 smitmnirmal@gmail.com 🥆 smitnirmal3597.github.io 📞 +1 (226) 759-3597

in linkedin.com/in/smitnirmal 🕤 github.com/smitnirmal3597

Full-Stack Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience in software development process. Strong knowledge of Object-Oriented Programming Languages, Data Structures and Algorithms. Understanding of SDLC to deliver quality and consistency in performance. True team player with well-developed analytical, problem-solving, interpersonal, written and verbal communication skills acquired through professional work experience.



Education

Master of Applied Computing, *University of Windsor*

Jan 2019 - Aug 2020

Bachelors of Computer Engineering, Ganpat University

Aug 2014 - May 2018



Skills

Languages

Python, Java, C#, .NET Core, ASP.NET, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS

Database

MongoDB, Redis, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MS SQL Server, SQLite, **Firebase**

Cloud Tools

AWS, Microsoft Azure, Heroku

Project/Code Management Tools

Git, JIRA, Bitbucket, SDLC, Agile, **SCRUM**

Frameworks

Angular, Node.js, React, Express.js, .NET, Entity Framework, Ionic, Flask

Others

Nginx, jQuery, JSON, XML, Postman, Chrome Dev Tools, Docker, **Kubernetes**



Professional Experience

Software Consultant, BDO Canada

Mar 2021 – present

Technologies: C#, .Net Core, Angular, HTML, SCSS, TypeScript, SQL Server, Azure DevOps, JIRA, Jenkins

- Understand and help refine un-stated requirements & work with the Development Manager, Business Analyst, and Project Manager to define software requirements and to assess the feasibility of solutions within time constraints
- Delivering development activities on time and on budget per project plan by producing quality code that is secure, reliable, reusable, and scalable
- Participate in pull-reguest reviews and help team members to solve their technical difficulties

Programmer Analyst-Intern, Ontario Teachers' Pension Plan

Jan 2020 – Aug 2020

Technologies: Angular, Python, C#, ASP.NET, Docker, Kubernetes, MySQL, Apache ActiveMQ, Redis

- Responsible for developing micro-services in Angular, ASP.NET, Spring Boot and Python, also containerized them using Docker and orchestrated using Kubernetes
- Built back-end REST APIs using Flask and .NET; performed Unit and Integration testing
- Duties included meeting with business partners, scrum masters and OA to identify and groom new functionality, upgrade existing functionality and system design changes in Agile-Scrum environment

Software Developer (Part-time), Bidja Innovations Inc.

Jan 2019 - Dec 2019

Technologies: Angular, Node.js, Ionic, Apache Cordova, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Firebase, JSON, Bitbucket

- Day to day duty included developing mobile application which connects to CNC machine and fetches live JSON data using Rest API; updated and maintained the data in firebase database
- Designed User Interface using web technologies such as Angular, Bootstrap 4, Ionic framework, HTML and CSS
- Utilized Apache Cordova to add native-app functionalities by ensuring that application is Android/iOS compatible
- Collaborated remotely with multiple team members in order to meet deliverable on time using GitHub

Achievements

- Participated in various academic coding competitions and secured top ranks in many of them
- Helped out participants during the coding competition for queries related to technical problems, provided resources
- Demonstrated various professional skills while working at Ontario Teachers' Pension Plan